本字幕由诸神字幕组出品，仅供学习交流
fortress Gujarat
更多中日双语字幕，尽在www.kamigami.org 及微博@诸神字幕组
連絡が入ったか
There is news?
は…はい
D-da.
ガーデーヴィが戦象部隊を連れ
Gadevi went from Uraiyura with war elephants.
ウライユールをたったようです
動いたか
Stir.
アンドラゴラス王でさえ
Even King Andragoras
正面から戦おうとしなかった戦象部隊がついに…
not trying to directly oppose these war elephants.
それと…
And further...
なんだ
What?
ラジェンドラ軍がガーデーヴィ軍の背後に回ったと
According to reports, Rajendra army bypassed Gadevi troops from the rear.
どうも私が考えていた状況の中で
It seems that of all possible situations and costed me
we are waiting for the most ridiculous of them.
最もばかばかしい事態になったようです
パルス暦３２１年　初頭
The era of Parsis, the beginning of the year 321.
無双と名高い戦象部隊を率い　ガーデーヴィ軍１５万が動いた
Taking with him elephants, which have no equal,
one hundred and fifty thousand people Gadevi army moved on the battlefield.
Against them came the combined forces of Rajendra and Arslan.
対するは　ラジェンドラとアルスラーンの連合軍
But their army numbered only sixty thousand,
しかし　その兵力は６万と　差は歴然であった
difference in strength was obvious.
王位簒奪を企てるラジェンドラを討つ
Destroy Rajendra, who intends to seize the throne!
Crown Prince sindoor, Gadevi
大義は我らにあり
We have a worthy goal!
ガーデーヴィは連戦連敗
Gadevi lost all their matches!
The second prince of the kingdom sindoor, Rajendra
自らの無能をさらした
All have seen his incompetence!
流れは俺たちにある
日听&翻译
小伍
sora
兰樱
校对
小江
mam
片源
Rei
时间轴
钦钦&雪糕
压制
久嘉
Coolkid
Chapter XVI
ここに我がパルス軍が１万
Here are our ten thousand parsiantsev.
ここにガーデーヴィ軍が１５万
Here one hundred and fifty thousand people Gadevi.
そして　ここにラジェンドラ軍が５万
And here fifty thousand people Rajendra.
挟み撃ちか
They're right between us.
本来なら戦術的に有利だが…
Normally we would have a tactical advantage, but ...
はい
Yes. When the enemy outnumber us,
敵の数が圧倒的に多い場合　意味をなしません
it does not matter.
例えば　ガーデーヴィ軍２万ほどの兵をパルス軍に当て　動きを封じる
For example, nearly twenty thousand army Gadevi
can go to catch Parsis army.
その間に　残り１３万の兵でラジェンドラをたたく
Meanwhile
the remaining one hundred and thirty thousand will go towards Rajendra army.
そうなれば　我々の負けです
And then we will be destroyed.
So we're at a disadvantage.
戦況は圧倒的に不利か
どの面下げて戻ってきた
How dare you come back here ?!
グジャラート城が落ちたのは貴様の落ち度だ
You are to blame for the loss of the fortress of Gujarat!
申し訳ございません
I am sorry.
Slave Mahendra of sindoor, Jaswant
ガーデーヴィ様
Prince Gadevi!
As long as you are not covered anger
お怒りはごもっともながら
Hereditary Grand Vizier kingdom sindoor, Mahendra
どうか　償いの機会を
I ask you to give a chance to atone.
どういうつもりだ　間者ごときに
What does it mean? For a simple spy?
マヘーンドラの顔を立て
Out of respect for Mahendra
I leave your body until the head.
貴様の首は一時　胴体に預けておく
But...
だが…
今後また失敗があれば　容赦せぬ
If it persists, it will be no mercy.
I understand.
承知しております
ご安心ください
Keep calm.
Their firepower is inferior to ours.
戦力はいまだ我らの方がはるかに上
負ける可能性など万に一つもございません
There is no chance that we will lose them.
当たり前だ
Of course!
大丈夫か　ジャスワント
Are you okay, Jaswant?
申し訳ございません
I'm sorry.
Due to my problems and miss you, Mr. Mahendra ...
私の失策で　マヘーンドラ様にまでご迷惑を
あれはお前のせいではない
It is not your fault.
パルスの軍師の知恵が並外れていただけだ
Just tactics Parsis
It proved to be very inventive.
ガーデーヴィ様は他人に対して慈悲がなさすぎる
Gadevi Prince did not sympathize with others.
あれでは臣下の心が離れていくばかりだ
At this rate, he will lose all his loyal subjects.
臣下の心…
Loyal subjects ...
The prince and his subjects really cared about each other.
あの王子と臣下たちは　互いをよく思い合っていた
ガーデーヴィが軍を２つに分けたようだ
It seems Gadevi divided the army into two parts.
一方を俺たちのところへ
One of them is sent to us,
and the second was sent to Rajendra.
もう一方をラジェンドラの軍へ向かわせている
お前の予想どおりに事が動いたな
Everything goes as you predicted.
Because it is a standard ploy.
それが用兵の常道だからな
だが　ガーデーヴィは我らパルス軍の真価を知らぬ
Only Gadevi unknown true value of Parsis army.
しかし
But the battle for the throne between Gadevi and Rajendra
ガーデーヴィとラジェンドラの王位争いは考えさせられるものがあるな
It suggests one idea.
The conflict between the Prince Arslan and Hermes.
アルスラーン殿下とヒルメス王子の争いに重なって見えるか
At this thought?
ああ
Yes.
One day the prince will have to confront the prince Hermes.
いずれ殿下はヒルメス王子と対峙することになろう
一体どのような道を選ばれるのか
Which way then elect a prince?
そのときには
When this happens,
Prince's skills as a ruler will again be in doubt.
再び殿下の器が問われることになるだろうな
fields Chandigarh
パルス暦３２１年２月
The era of Parsis, February 321 years.
ラジェンドラ軍とガーデーヴィ軍は相対し
Army Rajendra Gadevi and they faced each other.
戦いの幕が切って落とされようとしていた
That's a fierce battle was about to begin.
army Rajendra
army Gadevi
ラジェンドラよ
Rajendra!
奴隷の子でありながら王位を狙う　身の程知らずが
The son of a slave who does not know his place and desired to ascend to the throne!
If slezesh a white horse, which does not suit you,
似合いもしない白馬から降りて土下座をすれば　命だけは助けてやろう
and will fall down in front of me, I'll spare you!
血統からいえば　はるかに優位なのに
Your family tree is much better than mine,
父は貴様を正式な王太子としなかった
but your father has never officially announced you the crown prince.
Because compared to me you're not worthy!
貴様自身が俺より見劣りするからよ
Why do not you admit it not?
認めたらどうだ
たたき潰せ
Destroy them!
In the attack!
かかれ
Forward!
進め
川のせいで軍が分断され
The river divides the army
ガーデーヴィ様の数の強さが生かせない
so the numerical advantage disappears Gadevi prince's army.
これもあの軍師の策か
This is also part of the ideas of this tactic?
ガーデーヴィ様　前線部隊が押されています
Prince Gadevi, the front line has shifted.
戦象部隊を出せ
Send elephants.
構え
Ready!
早いな　もう出てきたか
Fast. So already released.
弓箭隊前進　象どもに矢を浴びせろ
Send forward archers!
Absorb elephants arrows!
Aim!
構え
撃て
Fire!
構え
Aim!
撃て
Fire!
何やってる　撃て
Which froze? Fire!
なぜだ
How so ?!
寒さに弱い象どもがここまで動けるはずがない
Elephants do not tolerate the cold.
They had to retire from the battle.
象どもを興奮させ　戦わせるために薬物を使っているのでしょう
They must have used drugs,
from where the elephants go into a rage, and then send them into battle.
せめてパルスの騎馬隊がいれば…
Whether we Parsis cavalry ...
到着はまだか
They have not arrived yet?
報告申し上げます
I report.
パルス軍はグジャラート城において包囲され　足止めされているもよう
Parsis army surrounded the fortress of Gujarat,
they have to stay there!
何
What?!
fortress Gujarat
Heck.
パルス軍の助けは来ないということか
This means that we do not wait for help from the Parsa?
Unfortunately.
残念ながら…
勝負はついた
The battle is over.
Further confrontation will only lead to mass murder.
これ以上はただの虐殺だ
ラジェンドラ様
Prince Rajendra.
報告します　騎馬隊全滅です
Reporting! The cavalry destroyed!
後続部隊も壊滅状態
Reserve forces also broken!
Nothing more we can do.
もはや　なす術もありません
これ以上俺についてきた者たちを死なせるわけには…
These people followed me, I can not afford to have died more ...
これまでか…
So this is the end.
パルス軍が到着しました
Parsis army arrived!
アルスラーン殿
Prince Lions!
Black storm ...
黒い嵐だ…
俺が助けるつもりだったが…
I was going to rescue her ...
よそ見を
You do not...
面白くない
So uninteresting.
アルスラーン殿
Prince Lions!
グジャラート城で足止めされていると聞いたが
I heard that you were detained in the fortress of Gujarat ...
どうやってここまで来られた
How did you get here?
ちょっと飛んでまいりました
We were in a hurry.
A?
まあ　今頃　城に入った兵士たちは地団駄を踏んでいるでしょうな
Well, the soldiers who just go broke,
stomp their feet in disgust.
中身のない張り子細工を血眼で見張っていたのですから
They are so closely watched
for blank paper tiger.
城の中には誰もいません
In the fortress there is no one.
どういうことだ
What does it mean?
Reporting.
報告します
パルス兵数名が裏門から逃走したもようです
Parsianskih Several soldiers have just escaped through the back gate.
何
What?!
そうか　本隊は俺たちが来る前に脱出していたのか
Clear!
So, the main forces were gone before we arrived!
くそっ
Heck!
くそっ　くそっ
Heck! Heck!
さすがはナルサス卿　聞きしに勝る策略家よ
What one would expect from Mr. Narsusa.
You are the best tactics of all, I know.
Flattered to hear that.
お褒めにあずかり光栄です
But the crucial point here.
しかし　ここからが正念場
The problem lies in the fighting elephants Gadevi.
問題はガーデーヴィの戦象部隊です
ああ
Yes.
Do not worry.
ご安心ください
我らパルス騎馬隊の真価はその機動力と柔軟な戦術にあります
The true power of the cavalry Parsis
It is their agility and tactical flexibility.
後衛の戦象部隊をパルス軍にたたきつけろ
Separate the army Parsis trailing war elephants!
狙いはパルス軍だ
The goal - the army Parsis!
潰せ
Crush them!
行くぞ
Forward!
集まれ
Link up!
見ろ　パルス兵どもが退いていくぞ
Look! Parsis army retreats!
我が戦象部隊には何者も勝てんのだ
Against my none shall stand elephants!
いけません　ガーデーヴィ様
Bad things, Prince Gadevi!
Something they have not.
ヤツら　何か変です
象たちを下がらせてください
Please revoke elephants.
何を言っている
What are you hanging?
今こそヤツらを壊滅させる好機だろうが
This is a great opportunity to destroy them!
パルス軍を徹底的に追い込め　俺も出るぞ
Crush the whole army Parsis to the last man!
I, too, get out!
ガーデーヴィ様
Prince Gadevi!
なんだ　あれは
What is it?!
Trap?!
罠か
止まれ
Stand!
象が命令を聞かない
Elephant does not listen!
なんと…
Wow...
もともと　象とは小回りの利かぬ動物
Elephants themselves are not that nimble creatures.
薬物で興奮しているとなれば　なおさら
And even more so when they are inflated drugs.
そして…
AND...
発射
Fire!
象の皮膚には矢は通りません
Arrows are not able to pierce the skin of an elephant.
故により大きな槍を使い　その穂先に毒を塗っておきました
Therefore, we used large spears treated with poison.
象を止めろ　ここからなら止まれるはずだ
Stop an elephant!
now we need to stay the same!
止まれ
Stay!
Stay! Stay!
止まれ　止まれ
ガーデーヴィ様　あの黒い騎士が…
Prince Gadevi, the black knight ...
殿下を守れ
Protect the prince!
武器は同じか
We own a weapon.
If we talk about the spear, that I am much more skillful!
槍に関しては　俺も腕に覚えがある
馬ごと踏み潰せ
Trample him with a horse!
There is!
はっ
覚悟
Get ready!
させぬ
I will not let it!
こらっ　何を
Hey, what are you? ..
Get out!
お乗りください
逃がすか
Do not go away!
Wait!
待ってくれ
頼む　撃たないでくれ
Please do not shoot.
殿下があの者をお助けになるのは　これで二度目でございます
Prince, you are already the second time saving this man.
あの者に恩を感じる心があればよろしゅうございますが
I hope that he will be grateful for it in my heart.
チャンディガルの野における戦いは終わった
Battle of the Chandigarh fields over.
Gadevi gave the elephants to be torn apart and fled.
ガーデーヴィは戦象部隊を壊滅させ　逃亡
ラジェンドラとパルス連合軍の勝利として　歴史に刻まれた
This battle is immortalized in the history of the battle the combined forces Rajendra and Parsis.
Royal capital Uraiyur Kingdom sindoor
なぜ　あの場で逃げた
Why did you run away ?!
お前は私を救ったなどと思ってはいまいな
Do not you think that you are thereby saved me!
いえ　そのような…
No, I would never ...
Because of the escape at that moment my army lost!
あの逃走で我が軍の敗北は決定した
逃げてはならなかったのだ
I had no right to do so!
But the Prince Gadevi ...
しかし　ガーデーヴィ様…
貴様は意見する前に　打開策を考えろ
And you think, before I dare to object!
I will not tolerate more of this!
これ以上の敗北は許さん
I got it.
承知しております
役立たずどもめ
Useless fools!
わしは補佐する相手を間違ったのかもしれん
Perhaps I made a mistake by agreeing to become your advisor.
申し訳ございません
I apologize.
I again
またしても　閣下の顔に泥を塗るようなまねを…
disgraced by his act of His Majesty's name.
何を言う
What are you?
お前がいなければ　ガーデーヴィ殿下は確実に討ち取られていた
If not you,
Prince Gadevi would already lay dead there.
Jaswant, we can only
ジャスワントよ
もはや我らは都の城壁を頼り　ラジェンドラを退けるしかない
relying on the walls of the royal capital in the victory over Rajendra.
頼りにしておるぞ
I count on you.
ありがたきお言葉
Thank you for those words.
I'm not capable of many things,
微力ではございますが　必ず閣下のお役に立たせていただきます
but always worthy to serve His Majesty.
急報です
Urgent Report.
国王陛下が目を覚まされました
His Majesty the King woke up.
父上
Father!
Ruler sindoor kingdom, Karikal II
おお　ガーデーヴィか
Is that you, Gadevi.
Glad to see you in good health.
よくぞ　お元気になってくださいました
変わりはないか
Nothing changed?
はい
No.
ラジェンドラも呼んできてくれ
Call-to court and Rajendra.
あやつの顔も見たい
I want to see him.
The thing is...
そのことでございます
弟が私を殺し　王位を奪おうとしているのです
The younger brother is trying to kill me and take the throne.
What?
何
Rajendra assembled soldiers, who followed him,
ラジェンドラは自分に従う兵士を集め
今もこの都に攻め入ろうとしています
and now he is trying to invade the capital.
I beg you, father,
どうか父上　争いを止めるため　ヤツに誅罰を与え
stop this battle, I will punish them
and declare me the heir to the throne.
私を正式に次期国王に…
Looks like,
おおかた　見苦しい兄弟ゲンカをしておるといったところじゃろう
you unleashed petty quarrel, as I feared.
まったく　お主らは…
Lord, what do you ...
で…ですが　父上
B-but ... father
わしは知恵に限りある身
My wisdom is not unlimited.
It seems I can only entrust the decision to the gods.
この裁断は　神々にお任せするしかあるまい
神前決闘によって　我が後継者を定めることとする
Heir to the throne is determined to fight the gods.
神前決闘
In a duel of the gods?
What is it?..
それは一体…
神前決闘とは　シンドゥラ国における特殊な裁判法と聞きます
Duel of the gods -
a special selection method in the kingdom sindoor.
争う２名が武器を取って決闘し
The two warring parties take up arms and fight,
and the winner is determined by the decision of the gods.
その勝者を神々の名において　正義と認める…という
Yes, still true.
そのとおりだ
つまり　俺とガーデーヴィが１対１で戦い
That is, I will meet with Gadevi in ​​the battle alone,
and the winner will be the next king.
勝った方が次期国王となる
シンドゥラの王様はよっぽど自分で責任を取るのがお嫌いらしいな
It seems that the king sindoor really do not want to take such a responsibility.
結局は　神々に判断を押しつけるだけか
He just shake off the decision on the Gods.
私も　ただ勝った方が正しいというやり方はおかしいと思う
I also believe that this method
determining the winner is very strange.
まこと　殿下のおっしゃるとおりでございます
Indeed, totally agree with you, Prince.
しかし　神前決闘にも利点があります
But also in the fight of the gods has its advantages.
それは？
What kind?
There is no need to send troops to perish.
軍を動かして殺し合う必要がない
That is, for this fight, only one person is needed.
つまり　犠牲者がただ１人で済むことです
But in a fight of the gods
この神前決闘だが　代理人に戦わせることもできる
you can set and their confidant.
So I have to ask you.
そこで　折り入って頼みがあるのだが…
ダリューン殿に俺の代理人として戦ってもらいたいのだ
I want Mr. Daryun made this confidant.
なっ…
どうか　アルスラーン殿　ダリューン殿　お願いする
I ask Prince Arslan, Mr Daryun. Help me!
What?
YakuSub Studio
kimi ga deatta kokoro wa kitto
All the souls that you could meet on the way,
translation Mu_Cool
hitotsu datte machigai janai
certainly it was pure and innocent,
Editorial Mu_Cool
onaji yume wo daite
We kept the same dream.
Making Helge
michi wo tagaeta hito wo omotta
People walking different paths,
nozarashi no akogare wo kakagete susumu kouya
killed all my hopes and desires revive again.
hohoemi mo sono namida mo
Smile on his face, tears running down her cheeks,
koko ni suteteyukenai kara
If you want to go ahead, they should not be forgotten.
kage wo daite shiroku takaku
Covered by the shadow of the summer, so white and immense,
namonaki boku to kimi no hata
our with you nameless flag flies.
mada hatenaku tsudzuku kono mich ino kanata ni
There, on the road, which extends an endless path,
tatta hitotsu no hikari wo sen no kokoro ni
There is one bright light, and with it a thousand souls.
miageru sora wo shinjiteru
Believe in the sky above his head,
michibiku hoshi wo higashi no takami ni sashishimesu yo
there putevodnaâ our star in the east, ee do not engage.
yume wa kono te de kanaeru
And their cherished dream in flesh forces.
ダリューンこそ
Is not all of Daryun
アルスラーンにとって大事な　本当に大事な部下ではないのか
the most important subject for Arslan?
ダリューンをこのような決闘に出したのは間違いではなかったのだろうか
There was a mistake to send Daryuna on this battle?
次回　神前決闘
Next time: "Duel of the gods."
Chapter XVII
少年は　そして王となる
And so the guy would be King.